dumbpassiveincome.com 2019-04-23

# Privacy Policy • The Dumb Passive Income Blog

### Privacy Policy for  **DumbPassiveIncome** **.com**

The Dumb Passive Income brand and DumbPassiveIncome.com are owned and operated by DPI Worldwide LLC.

At **DumbPassiveIncome** **.com** , the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information that is received and collected by **DumbPassiveIncome** **.com**  and how it is used.

### Log Files

Like many other Web sites, **DumbPassiveIncome** **.com**  makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

**DumbPassiveIncome** **.com** does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

#### Use of EziGDPR services

We use the encrypted third-party cookie `_ezigdpr_02d3c264acfe9ca1` on the domain `fast.ezigdpr.com` to store information about your citizenship status.

Data stored includes: a unique anonymous identifier; your citizenship status (yes/no) and the date you made the selection.

For non European Union vistors (i.e. “No” selection), we also store the IP address used to make selection, which allows for a more complete audit trail.

This data, as well as a log of changes to the data, is stored in the EziGDPR database. For more information, visit [www.ezigdpr.com](https://www.ezigdpr.com/).

#### Third-Party Disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it’s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

#### Third-party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### DoubleClick DART Cookie

.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on **DumbPassiveIncome** **.com**.

.:: Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to **DumbPassiveIncome** **.com**  and other sites on the Internet.

.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners may include, but are not limited to…….

  * Google Adsense
  * Amazon Affiliates

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on **DumbPassiveIncome** **.com**  send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

**DumbPassiveIncome** **.com** has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. **DumbPassiveIncome** **.com** ‘s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

### CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred.

**To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:**

  * NOT use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can…**

Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

  * Users can visit our site anonymously.
  * Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

Within 7 business days…

  * We will notify the users via email
  * We will notify the users via in-site notification

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

### Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact me using the information below.

Email via my [Contact page](http://matt76allen.wpengine.com/contact-me/) or mail to:

DPI Worldwide LLC  
Attn: Matthew Allen  
1765 3 Mile Rd NE – 150352  
Grand Rapids, Michigan 49515  
United States

Phone: 724-326-3862

Last Edited on June 30, 2018
